https://www.elektron.se/privacy-policy/

Log out
Cart overviewYour cart is emptyShippingTotalClose CartCheckout >>
Privacy Policy
Who is the controller?
Elektron Music Machines Mav AB (Elektron), org.nr 556713-8093
Address: Sockerbruket 9, 414 51 Gothenburg, Sweden
E-mail: privacy@elektron.se
The Purposes and Legal Basis for our Processing of Personal Data
Performance of Purchase Agreement
When buying a product from Elektron you enter into a purchase agreement with us. Elektron processes data such as your name, address, e-mail, phone number, payment information, customer number and the serial number of your product for the purpose of performing your purchase agreement. The data is used to for example deliver your product, notify you when it has arrived, control your identity, handle payment and manage returns, support, complaints and warranty issues. The legal basis for this processing is that it is necessary for our performance of your purchase agreement or in order to take steps at the request of you prior to entering the purchase agreement. You are not obliged to provide the requested personal data, but if the data is not provided Elektron cannot enter into a purchase agreement with you.
Customer Account
You may register a Customer Account at Elektron to buy products and/or handle issues related to your Elektron product. When registering a Customer Account, we ask you to provide your e-mail address and a password for the purpose of managing your account. When an order or a support inquiry is placed for the first time, we ask you to provide us with your name, e-mail address, phone number and address for the purpose of handling issues related to your Elektron product,
for example to track your order and manage returns, support, complaints and warranty issues. The legal basis for this processing is that it is necessary to meet your and Elektron’s legitimate interest of handling issues related to your Elektron product and/or that it is necessary for our performance of your purchase agreement or in order to take steps at the request of you prior to entering the purchase agreement.
Elektronauts Account
When creating an account at Elektronauts we ask you to provide us with a username and password as well as your name and e-mail for the purpose of managing your account. You may also enter additional data in order to personalize your user profile and when participating in discussions. When registering an account and posting in the forum, Elektron also records your IP-address. The data is used to enable you to participate in Elektronauts discussion forum. The legal basis for this processing is that it is necessary in order to meet your and Elektron’s legitimate interest of managing your Elektronauts Account and participate in the Elektronauts discussion forum.
Marketing
If you choose to subscribe to our mailing list, Elektron uses your name and e-mail address for the purpose of direct marketing by sending you newsletters about for example our products, events and Sound Packs. The legal basis for this processing is that you have given consent to the processing of your e-mail address for the purpose of direct marketing and/or that it is necessary in order to meet Elektron’s legitimate interest of direct marketing our products and services.
Contact
If you contact us through our contact forms or by e-mailing us we will use the data you send to us, including for example your name and e-mail address, for the purpose of communicating with you and otherwise handle your inquiries and requests. The legal basis for this processing is that it is necessary to meet your and Elektron’s legitimate interest of contact and otherwise handling your request.
Career
If you send us your résumé or job application we will use the personal data you send to us to evaluate your skills profile matching of the job requirements and to contact you once the process is complete. The legal basis for this processing is that it is necessary in order to take steps at your request prior to entering an employment agreement and that the processing is necessary in order to meet your and Elektron’s legitimate interest handling your job application.
Legal obligations
Elektron may also process your personal data to comply with legal obligations, for example related to product safety, accounting and tax issues. The legal ground for this processing is that it is necessary for compliance with legal obligations to which Elektron is subject.
Recipients of your Personal Data
We do not sell or trade your personal data with third parties.
Elektron shares personal data with processors, such as firms assisting Elektron in operating our site, logistics and shipping companies, payment service companies and marketing firms, who process your personal data on Elektron’s behalf. When doing so Elektron always makes sure to have relevant data protection agreements in place to safeguard your personal data and make sure that it is only processed for our intended purpose.
When legally obliged to do so, Elektron may also share your personal information with public authorities who are independent controllers and thus process your data for the purposes and means determined by them. When delivering your products Elektron may also share your information with bodies handling the general transport of goods.
Is Your Data Transferred to Third Countries?
If you choose to subscribe to our mailing list, Elektron transfers your e-mail address to The Rocket Science Group (MailChimp), which is part of the U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. The EU Commission has decided that companies who are part of this framework ensures an adequate level of protection.
For How Long Does Elektron Store Your Personal Data?
Personal Data which has been collected for the performance of a purchase agreement is as a main rule stored during one year after the end of the product’s warranty time, provided that there are no outstanding issues related to the product and that Elektron does not have a legal obligation to save the data longer. Elektron will however store information related to the functionality of our products, including their serial numbers, during ten years after the transaction date in order to give you and potential future owners a high quality of service in relation to the specific product.
Information which has been registered in relation to your Customer Account and Elektronauts Account will be stored for as long as the account is active. If you choose to close down your Elektronauts Account, all data relating to your account will be erased. If you choose to close your Customer Account, Elektron will close your account. Elektron will however store the information on your Customer Account in accordance with the principles outlined in the above section.
We will store your name and e-mail address for the purpose of direct marketing until you object to this or withdrawal your consent. If you do so, we will immediately erase the data from the list.
Résumés and job applications will be deleted within a year after you have sent these to Elektron. E-mails, which are not related to purchase agreements or your Elektron products, will be deleted within half a year.
Your Rights
You have a number of rights concerning the processing of your personal data and you are always welcome to contact us concerning this on privacy@elektron.se. According to GDPR you for example have a right to, under certain conditions:
be informed of how your data is being used by Elektron and its processors;
access personal data that Elektron has about you;
ask Elektron to correct inaccurate personal data;
require Elektron to delete your personal data;
request transfer of your data to another controller;
object to certain kinds of processing; and
ask us to restrict the processing of your personal data.
You Have the Right to Withdraw Your Consent
Where Elektron processes personal data based on your consent, you always also have the right to withdraw the consent. This will however not affect the lawfulness of processing based on you consent that has taken place before the consent was withdrawn.
Direct Marketing
You always have the right to object to our processing of your personal data for the purpose of direct marketing and profiling to the extent that it is related to such direct marketing. Elektron will then make sure to cease the use of your data for direct marketing.
Complaints
If you need more information about our processing of personal data or have questions or complaints you are always welcome to contact us on privacy@elektron.se.
You have the right to lodge a complaint to a supervisory authority, which in Sweden is Datainspektionen (https://www.datainspektionen.se).
Changes to the Privacy Policy
This Privacy Policy was last updated on May 23, 2018. Elektron may update this Privacy Policy from time to time and will inform you of the updates by e-mail and through this website. Please make sure to keep yourself updated on the latest version.
Who We Are
Contact Us
Store Locator
Privacy Policy
Terms and Conditions
Downloads
Press
Careers
Select your countryAfghanistanAland IslandsAlbaniaAlgeriaAmerican Minor Outlying IslandsAmerican SamoaAmerican Virgin IslandsAndorraAngolaAnguillaAntarcticaAntigua and BarbudaArgentinaArmeniaArubaAustraliaAustriaAzerbaijanBahamasBahrainBangladeshBarbadosBelarusBelgiumBelizeBeninBermudaBhutanBoliviaBonaire, Sint Eustatius and SabaBosnia and HerzegovinaBotswanaBouvet IslandsBrazilBritish Indian Ocean TerritoryBritish Virgin IslandsBrunei DarussalamBulgariaBurkina FasoBurundiCambodiaCameroonCanadaCape VerdeCayman IslandsCentral African RepublicChadChileChinaChristmas IslandCocos (Keeling) IslandsColombiaComorosCongoCook IslandsCosta RicaCote d'IvoireCroatiaCubaCuraçaoCyprusCzech RepublicDemocratic Republic of the CongoDenmarkDjiboutiDominicaDominican RepublicEcuadorEgyptEl SalvadorEquatorial GuineaEritreaEstoniaEthiopiaFalkland IslandsFaroe IslandsFijiFinlandFranceFrench GuyanaFrench PolynesiaFrench Southern TerritoriesGabonGambiaGeorgiaGermanyGhanaGibraltarGreeceGreenlandGrenadaGuadeloupeGuamGuatemalaGuernseyGuineaGuinea-BissauGuyanaHaitiHeard and McDonald IslandsHondurasHong KongHungaryIcelandIndiaIndonesiaIranIraqIrelandIsle Of ManIsraelItalyJamaicaJapanJerseyJordanKazakhstanKenyaKiribatiKuwaitKyrgyzstanLaosLatviaLebanonLesothoLiberiaLibyaLiechtensteinLithuaniaLuxembourgMacaoMadagascarMalawiMalaysiaMaldivesMaliMaltaMarshall IslandsMartiniqueMauretaniaMauritiusMayotteMexicoMicronesiaMoldovaMonacoMongoliaMontenegroMontserratMoroccoMozambiqueMyanmarNamibiaNauruNepalNetherlandsNew CaledoniaNew ZealandNicaraguaNigerNigeriaNiueNorfolk IslandsNorth KoreaNorth MacedoniaNorth Mariana IslandsNorwayOmanPakistanPalauPalestine, State ofPanamaPapua New GuineaParaguayPeruPhilippinesPitcairn IslandsPolandPortugalPuerto RicoQatarRepublic of South SudanReunionRomaniaRussian FederationRwandaSaint BarthélemySaint Kitts and NevisSaint MartinSamoaSan MarinoSao Tome and PrincipeSaudi ArabiaSenegalSerbiaSeychellesSierra LeoneSingaporeSint MaartenSlovakiaSloveniaSolomon IslandsSomaliaSouth AfricaSouth Georgia and the Southern Sandwich IslandsSouth KoreaSpainSri LankaSt. HelenaSt. LuciaSt. Pierre and MiquelonSt. VincentSudanSurinameSvalbardSwedenSwitzerlandSyriaTaiwanTajikistanTanzaniaThailandThe Kingdom of EswatiniTimor-LesteTogoTokelau IslandsTongaTrinidad,TobagoTunisiaTurkeyTurkmenistanTurksh CaicosinTuvaluUgandaUkraineUnited Arab EmiratesUnited KingdomUnited StatesUruguayUzbekistanVanuatuVatican CityVenezuelaVietnamWallis and Futuna IslandsWest SaharaYemenZambiaZimbabwe
Got it!This site makes use of cookies to save preferences, logins and shopping carts. By continuing to use this site you approve of such use of cookies.
